TYE BARRETT, MBA, PMP

PRODUCT INNOVATOR

ABOUT ME

experience conceptualizing competitive and disruptive B2B and B2C products for Fortune 100s to startups in the cannabis, entertainment, jewelry, manufacturing, retail and CPG industries. Led, develop and implement activities throughout the product lifecycle from strategic planning to prototype development to go-tomarketing strategy to sales performance.

CORE COMPETENCIES

- Strategic Planning
- Product Development & Mgmt.
- Creative Development
- · Packaging Design
- Licensing Partnerships
- Digital Media
- Process Improvement & Mgmt.
- P&L Budgeting/ROI Analysis
- Marketing & Brand Strategy
- Sales Performance & Forecasting
- Vendor Mgmt. & Contract Negotiation
- Risk & Issue Mitigation
- Team Building & Leadership

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Salesforce
- IIRA
- Asana
- Trello
- Skype
- Confluence
- Clarity
- MS Project
- SharePoint
- SAP
- SQL
- ServiceNow
- Visio
- ERP
- Facebook Ads

- Google Analytics
- Monday
- · CMS
- Omniture
- Microsoft Suite
- SaaS
- · Adobe Suite
- · Google AdWords
- Microsoft Azure
- · Amazon Web Serv
- OCM
- Oracle
- lava
- Windows

CONTACT

tyeeshabarrett@gmail.com (818) 850-1479

www.linkedin.com/in/tyeeshabarrett www.tyebarrett.me

EXPERIENCE

CANNDESCENT, CULVER CITY, CA | April 2019 to Present

Top-seller for luxury cannabis products.

Head of Project Management, Commercialization & Innovation

- · Erect and manage product development process from ideation to execution. Introduce the stagegate model to manage to institute governance throughout the product lifecycle from cradle to grave. Conduct feasibility studies, R&D and product testing. Design prototypes and packaging. Develop product briefs, BOMs and COGs. Oversee the development of creative briefs, marketing plans, partnerships, demand forecasts, pricing, value propositions, sell sheets, launch plans, promotional programs and account-specific programs.
- · Advise senior management and cross-functional leaders on strategic goals, branding, creative direction, roadmaps, go-to-market strategies, and product innovation/commercialization. Define product strategy. Conduct competitive analyses. Reposition and identify exiting strategies to recover underperforming products and recuperate profit loss. Ensure financial goals and investor
- Spearhead brainstorming sessions. Build business cases to obtain leadership buy-in. Facilitate kickoff, status, creative review and standup meetings. Develop critical paths, project plans and work breakdown structures. Reprioritize workloads, redirect resources, and adjust schedules to ensure deadlines are met. Devise action plans to mitigate risks/issues. Ensure roles and responsibilities are properly defined. Escalate concerns to stakeholders when project health and delivery is being jeopardized.
- · Develop project closures. Complete retrospectives. Review lessons learned and KPIs to ensure success criteria, project goals and customer expectations have been met. Identify opportunities/challenges to implement process improvements.
- Manage vendor and co-manufacturers domestically and internationally. Negotiate contracts. Brand white label products to accelerate speed-to-market, surpass core competencies and maximize revenue opportunities.

MEDMEN, CULVER CITY, CA | 2018 to March 2019

Largest cannabis retailer in the nation.

Senior Project Manager, Commercialization & Innovation

- Oversaw product innovation and commercialization of proprietary cannabis products.
- · Collaborated with departmental leaders for R&D, Demand Planning, Compliance, Product Development, Manufacturing, Sourcing, Marketing, Retail and C-Suite to ensure project delivery.
- Developed prototypes, demand forecasts, labor plans, BOMs, SOPs and COGs.

WARNER BROS., TECHNOLOGY DEPARTMENT, BURBANK, CA | 2017 to 2018 Provided technology solutions for all studio divisions.

Project Manager

- Administered business solutions. Oversaw the implementation of a POS system for US and UK locations: improved operational efficiency corporate-wide, gathered business intelligence to render key decisions and generate reports used by Sales and Marketing departments, and integrated ticketing, retail, and food & beverage processes. Managed the application backlog for bugs and system upgrades.
- Shepherded the development of website, portal and mobile application to advance inventory management, enhance customer experience and improve employee growth for the Costume department.
- Ensured regulatory compliance of IT systems. Managed Qualified Security Assessor (QSA). Reviewed and monitored PCI controls.

DISNEY, DTSS DIGITAL MEDIA AGENCY, BURBANK, CA | 2017

Internal digital media agency that serves Disney divisions corporate-wide.

Digital Media Project Manager

- Consulted on website and application development.
- Advised on business strategy, project management, requirements gathering, vendor selection, contract negotiation, user experience, technology, solution evaluation, hosting, security best practices, Web analytics and SEO.

HONDA, TORRANCE, CA | 2016 to 2017

One of the largest manufacturers of automobiles and motorcycles in the world.

Senior Project Manager

- Delivered IT projects (cyber security, cloud-based, infrastructure redesigns, software upgrades, vulnerability assessments, mobile) global-wide throughout all phases of SDLC. Transformed "red" fast-track projects to "green": scheduled daily scrum meetings, incorporated agile methodologies in a waterfall environment, provided complete project transparency to stakeholders, assessed complex work-streams to identify critical paths, differentiated between must-have and nice-to-have requirements and obtained executive support for major project changes.
 - Advised internal clients during business planning: reviewed current state and legacy technologies, identified opportunities for innovation improvements, reviewed preplanned and in-flight projects within the portfolio, forecasted project budgets to seek funding, developed high-level requirements to design system infrastructures, and prioritized projects based on severity.
- Interfaced with cross-functional teams including engineers, architects, product managers, SMEs, GRC (Governance Risk Management & Compliance) to deliver exceptional products and deliverables to customers.

EXPERIENCE

SIGNET JEWELERS (KAY, JARED, ZALES) | 2013 to 2016

Largest specialty jewelry retailer in the US, UK and Canada operating 3,600 stores with sales of approximately \$6B.

Marketing & Product Manager

- Developed the retail marketing and innovation process for proprietary products and brands. Supervised marketing process from strategic planning to tactical execution for brand/product launches, customer loyalty programs, and e-commerce/brick-and-mortar promotions. Wrote value propositions to execute brand strategy. Prepared and managed promotional calendars, marketing plans, creative briefs and budgets.
- Lead the creative development process from conception to execution. Facilitated ideation and creative review meetings with C-Suite. Oversaw the development of creative concepts. Coordinated photo shoots. Spearheaded the development of employee-facing and customer-facing marketing materials including product launch announcements, brand profiles, training tools, brochures, catalogs, social media assets, digital ads, emails, TV/radio commercials and in-store signage.
- Established licensing partnership opportunities. Partnered with *Lucas Films* to produce exclusive *Star Wars* jewelry. Tied partnership to film *The Force Awakens* and utilized all distribution channels to generate sales leads, elevate brand exposure and improve product sell-thru. Boosted sales and recovered loss for underperforming merchandise.
- Collaborated with Merchandising, Operations, Market Research/CRM, Public Relations, Social Media, Creative Services, Digital Marketing and Visual Merchandising, Credit and Corporate Partners.
- Met financial objectives by forecasting requirements, preparing an annual budget, analyzing variances and initiating corrective actions resulting in sales surpassing prior year.

GUITAR CENTER, WESTLAKE VILLAGE, CA | 2012 to 2013

Largest retailer of musical instruments grossing over \$2B including the subsidiaries Musicians Friend, Music 123 and Woodwind & Brasswind.

Creative Services Project Manager

Developed and executed retail marketing programs to promote products. Designed vendor-sponsored sweepstakes, special events, financing programs, customer loyalty programs, social media campaigns, promotional offers, employee contests and in-store activities to introduce new products, increase market share and generate revenue.

MARKETING CONSULTANT, LOS ANGELES, CA | 2009 to 2011

 Managed marketing projects for social media, digital marketing, website development, and event-planning projects for FanScape (digital marketing company), Machinima (major YouTube Partner) and others.

DISNEY CONSUMER PRODUCTS, BURBANK, CA | 2007 to 2009

Formerly Walt Disney Studios Home Entertainment, engages in licensing opportunities of Disney merchandise.

Retail Marketing Manager

- Relaunched and repositioned Blu-ray products. Partnered with studio competitors to declare as market leader. Conducted RCA (Root Cause Analysis) to identify issues and reposition the product line. Developed tools to educate and build awareness. Developed contests, coupons and promotional bundles to convert customers.
- Devised retail marketing plans for home entertainment CPGs including New Release, TV, Catalog and direct-to-video titles. Conducted business reviews, managed product P&Ls, forecasted sales, developed competitive marketing strategies, produced post-mortem reports for retail accounts. Ensured campaigns aligned with strategic goals.
- Collaborated with other divisions (Theatrical, ABC Network, Disneyland) to develop integrated product marketing programs that achieved corporate synergy, increased franchise exposure and maximized profit potential.

TIMKEN, CANTON, OH | 2006 to 2007

Global manufacturer of bearings and related components operating in 29 countries with sales of \$2.9B.

Marketing Communications Coordinator / Project Manager

- Collaborated with engineers, product managers and sales managers to cultivate strategic marketing communications plans for products in the Timken
 portfolio. Worked with counterparts in international markets to expand global market exposure.
- Developed sales tools to market products: articles, sell sheets, success stories, product descriptors, press releases, websites, advertisements, newsletters and brochures. Participated in tradeshows to build brand awareness and to exhibit product competitive advantages.

EDUCATION

MBA and Graduate Project Management Certificate, Marketing

University of Phoenix, Cleveland, OH

BA, Communications and BA, Journalism, Minor: Business Marketing

The Ohio State University, Columbus, OH

Project Management Certificate Program

Baldwin Wallace, Berea, OH

PMP (Project Management Professional)

PROFESSIONAL ORGANIZATIONS & AFFILIATIONS